Throughout this course, we'll concern ourselves
在整个课程中 我们将了解
with the idea of learning from interaction.
互动学习概念
In the field of reinforcement learning,
对于强化学习
we refer to the learner or decision maker as the agent.
我们将学习者或决策制定者称作智能体
But I really like dogs, so we'll instead,
但是我非常喜欢狗狗
think of the agent as a small puppy born into
因此我们将智能体看做一只
the world without any understanding of how anything works.
刚刚出生的小狗 对世界一点也不了解
And when he opens his eyes,
当它第一次睁开眼睛时
the first thing he observes is his owner.
首先看到的是它的主人
Now, say the owner communicates to the puppy how she would like it to behave.
假设主人向小狗发出行为指令
The puppy looks at the command and based on that observation,
小狗看着主人的手势并根据观察的结果
he's expected to choose how to respond.
做出如何响应的决定
Of course, he hasn't invested interest in responding appropriately,
当然 它还没有兴趣做出正确的响应
mostly to stay out of trouble but maybe to even get a treat.
主要是不惹麻烦 甚至获得奖赏
Now, newborn puppies are complicated creatures and it's
刚出生的小狗非常复杂
impossible to count the number of actions that he could take at any point in time.
根本无法计算它在任何时间可以采取的动作数量
Furthermore, he doesn't know what any of the actions
此外 它尚不知道任何动作
do yet or what effect will have on the world.
或者这些动作带来的影响
So we'll have to try them out and see what happens.
我们需要尝试这些指令并看看发生的结果
So how will he respond to his owners command?
小狗会如何对主人的指令做出响应？
At this point, he has no reason to favor any action over the others.
此刻 它不可能对一种动作更偏爱
And so, let's say he just picks one at random.
假设它只是随机选择一种动作
Of course, with full understanding that he has no idea what he's doing.
当然 它根本不知道自己的动作有什么含义
In this case, he decides to sit.
在这种情况下 它选择坐下
After taking this action,
完成这一动作后
he waits for a response.
它等待主人的响应
And I have to imagine the wait is pretty scary
可以想象等待非常长
as it's entirely uncertain what will happen next.
因为完全不清楚下一步会发生什么
In response to his action,
完成动作后
he receives feedback from his owner.
它从主人那获得了反馈
In this case, he receives a single treat.
在此示例中 它获得了一次奖赏
That's encouraging and he's off to a great start.
这很令他兴奋 它表现得不错
We'll assume that in general,
我们假设
his only goal is to maximize reward.
它的唯一目标是最大化奖励
He'd like it to be as positive as possible.
它希望一直表现得很正面
That holds for now and at every point in the future.
暂时是这种假设 以后也一直是这种假设
But now the owner has given
现在主人发出了新的指令
a new command and it's time for him to choose his next response.
它需要选择下一个响应
What do you think? Sitting seemed to perform well.
你认为呢？坐下似乎很合适
But now, the command looks different.
但是现在指令不一样了
So maybe a different action is more appropriate.
因此不同的动作可能更合适
He decides to again pick an action randomly.
它决定再次随机选择一个动作
In this case, he decides to run and waits for a response.
在此示例中 它决定奔跑并等待主人的响应
And, oh no, he received discouraging feedback from his owner.
糟糕 主人给出了负面反馈
Now, it's unclear if this is just a bad action in general
现在不清楚的是 奔跑是一般的负面动作
or if he should just not run in response to this particular observation.
还是不适合这个特定指令
He can only discover this through interacting more with
它只能通过系统地尝试和测试假设
his owner through systematically proposing and testing hypotheses.
与主人进行更多的互动来发现结果
And so the process continues where at each point in time,
这一流程继续下去
the puppy takes an action and then simultaneously
每一刻 小狗都采取一种动作
receives feedback and an updated observation from his owner.
同时获得反馈并获得主人的响应
At each point in time,
在每一刻
he does his best to execute the appropriate action to make his owner happy.
它都尽量采取合适的动作 使主人开心
Now at first glance, it could seem that when we view interaction along these lines,
咋一看 当我们以这种方式看待互动时
everything is pretty simple.
一切似乎都很简单
After all, the way the puppy interacts with his owner is quite systematic.
毕竟小狗与主人的互动非常具有系统性
And while it may take him some time to get an idea of what's happening,
虽然它可能需要一段时间才明白所发生的情况
he should be able to figure it out eventually.
但是它应该最终会明白的
But as you progress through this course,
在你学习这门课程的过程中
you'll see that this puppy situation is surprisingly complex.
你会发现这种小狗情形非常复杂
For instance, he'll have to find the balance with on
例如 它需要在以下两种情形之间找到平衡点
the one hand exploring potential hypotheses for how to choose actions.
一方面 探索如何选择动作的潜在假设
And on the other,
另一方面
exploiting his limited knowledge about what he already knows should work well.
探索已有的可行有限知识
That is, should he settle for just one treat or should he aim higher?
也就是说 它应该满足于一个奖赏 还是希望获得更多的奖赏
This is a very important concept in reinforcement learning.
这是强化学习中的一个非常重要的概念
While there are some widely adopted techniques
虽然对于如何平衡这两项要求
for balancing these two competing requirements,
有一些广泛采用的技巧
this question has inspired an entire subfield of reinforcement learning,
但是这个问题推动了一个完整的强化学习分支领域的出现
and remains an area of active research.
并且成为一个热点研究领域
Another thing that's important to note is that if
另一个值得注意的要点是
our puppy is truly a reinforcement learning agent,
如果小狗真的是强化学习智能体
he's not just concerned with the reward he can get now.
那么它不仅关心现在可以获得的奖励
Instead, his goal is to maximize
而且要最大化在一生中
the total number of treats he can get over his entire lifetime.
可以获得的奖励数量
So while it might be relatively simple to
因此发现在短期内效果不错的策略
derive a strategy that works well in the short term,
可能相对来说比较简单
he'll have to be a bit more clever if he wants to
但是如果要得出长期效果不错的策略
find strategies that take longer to pay off.
小狗就必须更加聪明
In general, this idea of learning from experience is intellectually quite interesting.
通常 这种通过经验学习规律的概念从学术上来说比较有趣
For instance, if you've ever tried to train a dog
例如 如果你训练过小狗
perhaps you've noticed that it's not so easy.
可能就会发现过程并不简单
His first instinct might be whenever I sit I receive
它的第一反应可能是每当我坐下来就能获得奖励
a treat rather than whenever my owner says sit and then I sit,
而不是每当主人说坐下来 我坐下来
I receive a treat.
就能获得奖励
Even though it seems like a reasonable mistake to make,
虽然你的智能体通常会犯错
we guarantee you that your agents will know better.
但是向你保证 它会学会更多知识的